Het Makadia Software Developer

in www.linkedin.com/in/hetmakadia

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer with a **Bachelor's degree** in **Computer Science** from California State University, Long Beach. Experienced in full-stack development using **React.JS**, **Angular.JS**, **.NET Framework**, **C#**, **Java**, **and Python**. Skilled in designing, coding, testing, and debugging software applications. Familiar with database management systems like **SQL Server**, **Firebase** and **MongoDB** and the Agile development process. Recognized on the President's Honor List, with a focus on building easy-to-use, practical applications. Enjoys working with teams to deliver reliable software solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Developer

10/2023 – present

M. S. International

- Developing and maintaining over 8 company software applications using .NET Framework, Bootstrap, C#, JavaScript, SQL, and APIs, resulting in updated UI and improved logic to meet business needs.
- Streamlining project delivery by providing regular updates and tracking progress through **JIRA**, enhancing team coordination and improving efficiency in meeting deadlines

Application Development Intern

06/2022 - 05/2023

EMPLOYERS Insurance Group, Inc.

- Transformed an Excel-based application into a modern web platform, "Access Report," using **Angular v16**, **TypeScript**, and **Java**, with **MongoDB** for backend data management, effeciently making the Approval Process faster around 40%.
- Collaborated in an Agile environment, leveraging **JIRA** for project tracking and task management, ensuring seamless **team coordination** and **efficient development**, enabling the completion of the project **1 month ahead of schedule**.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

01/2019 - 05/2023

California State University, Long Beach

PROJECTS

Supreme Carbon Website

02/2024 - 04/2024

React.js, JavaScript, ES6, Firebase, Google Maps, Tailwind CSS, JSON, Github

- Designed and developed the <u>official website</u> for **Supreme Carbon**, a manufacturing business in India, achieving a **20% increase in user engagement** by showcasing business and factory operations through a responsive and user-friendly interface.
- Managed the complete lifecycle of the project, including domain registration, hosting configuration, and deployment on **GitHub Pages**, integrating modern web technologies to deliver a high-performance website.

Rooster Web Application

08/2022 - 04/2023

React.js, JavaScript, ES6, Firebase, GitHub, Tailwind CSS, JSON

- Collaborated on the design and development of a comprehensive **roommate finder web application** for a Senior Project, implementing features such as user matching, advanced search filters, in-app messaging, mini-games, and account management to address the needs of students and professionals seeking compatible roommates.
- Analyzed **user requirements**, created detailed **software development documentation**, and contributed to coding, testing, and deployment, ensuring an intuitive, secure, and scalable application optimized for both desktop and mobile platforms.

Real Estate Website

08/2022 - 12/2022

React.js, JavaScript, ES6, SQL, GitHub, Bootstrap

- Played a vital role as a member of a collaborative team of 4 in the development of a website for a realtor real world client, contributing to both frontend and backend development while gathering client's requirement and following SDLC.
- Successfully implemented key features like **Google Maps API**, **Calendly API**, and an **Admin Panel**, increasing client efficiency by **25%** by implementing features to streamline scheduling and property management.

SKILLS

Frontend: ReactJS, AngularJS, JavaScript, ES6, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, Bootstrap, JSON, Material UI

Backend: Java, C#, Python, .NET

Database: Firebase, MongoDB, SQL Server

Source Control/IDE/Software: GitHub, Azure DevOps Server, JIRA, Bitbucket, Trello, IntelliJ Idea, PyCharm, WebStorm,

Visual Studio Code

Other: Software Development Life Cycle, Agile Methodology, Object Oriented Programming, Algorithms, Data Structures